Hello everyone. Thanks for coming. How
are you feeling?
>> Good. Second day. Awesome.
>> Who have coded in the past week?
>> Love to see.
>> Keep your hands up if you used AI.
Keep your hands up if you use AI and
spend more time fixing the code or
creating documentation or you know
wrangle with the code. Of course I'll
you can you know get your hand down. You
don't need that with Kira. Um yeah so I
think u like obviously things have
changed quite a bit right in the in the
past few years with the introduction of
AI to our uh lives. basically
um everywhere in in our lives it you
know it introduced different uh type of
capabilities and um in a way smart way
to do things and obviously on the coding
side uh we have used that in very
different ways with the code completion
and then uh you know they started
building the code by themselves which is
great. However,
it almost feels like these
capabilities or these models are just
spitting code at the light speed, but
there's a lot of oversight that you need
to do afterwards, right? You never 100%
sure if they're working fine or if
they're actually exactly to your uh um
specifications or requirements that you
that you're looking for. I kind of
always um looked at it from
like working with a contractor or
someone you can ask someone to build
something like for example if you think
about this room you can say hey I want
to build this room and I want to this to
be a multifunctional place and I want
some you know art you know around the
walls
you'll probably get
at least a few thousand different
variations depending on who you're
asking this, when you're asking this,
and how they're doing doing things. So,
basically with Kira, we're trying to
take all this complexity, all this all
the unknowns out of the way. And that's
why um the team was working hard to
bringing some of the best practices in
the software development life cycle to
an IDE where you can really trust the
code that you're building and we have
introduced a few few different things.
Obviously uh if you have attended Al's
um talk earlier in in the day he was
talking about spec driven development
obviously you heard from Burk and Victor
earlier about you know different um
tools in the market and how they uh use
those uh with ko um you can think like
just to recap some of the stuff that was
discussed in the prior session um
we have introduced things like
specifications.
So you basically say okay this is what
I'm going to build. This is what I need
you to build and these are the things
the steps that I will be following. The
second um area is the hooks. It's like
the agents right? So you it it can be
basically you can think them in simple
terms just the agents that run on
certain actions. So for example, when
you save a file, the hook can
automatically be triggered and it can
run to do certain tasks on behalf of you
in without you have to go back and
prompt again and again. We have also uh
obviously have remote MCP support so we
can supply all that uh additional
context or information that you need
from the various different systems.
Obviously documentation is the um
easiest one but if you have different
systems that you need to connect obvious
obviously you can do that too. So
with that being said
we have shown a lot of slides a lot of
different things throughout the day and
we wanted to dedicate this to a live
demo and again this is going to be a
live demo. We have some backups in place
but things can go wrong. So you know um
typical live demo thing. I'm uh ownores.
I lead our uh developer advocacy team in
North America uh at AWS and I have the
um privilege to work with some of the
greatest uh developer advocates in the
in the country. that um I'm happy to
introduce Jonathan to the demo and we'll
be basically showing some of the um ways
to work with Kira and we'll actually
build a application together using
agents and um Kira is the ID
know each other.
>> That's right.
>> Thank you owner. Hey everybody, my name
is Jonathan Vogle. I'm a developer
advocate at AWS and I'm super involved
in the Curo community. Today I'm going
to live demo with the intention of
working backwards from our abstract of
contextaware
AI coding and we're going to build some
agents.
So we have Kira open here on the screen
and you'll see on the right.
>> Oh, I see. All right. Thank you for the
heads up.
Can we see the ID now?
>> We can.
>> Fantastic. Thank you. All right. So, on
the right, you'll see the let's build
prompt. And if you got a chance to see
Al's talk, he he dove deep into specs.
Today, we're going to vibe given the
time constraint. And we're going to
start with building an agent with
Strands. Anyone familiar with Strand's
SDK? It's an open source SDK from AWS to
build agents. So, let's build a strands
agent that generates a dad joke by
calling the LLM.
Let's see what Kira comes up with. Now,
if you note,
I have auto mode here with Kira and
under the hood, it's invoking a model
and that model may not have training
data on strands. Strands is only
available in Python today. And we can
see already it's generating JavaScript
code. That's not what we want. And this
is a prime example of how AI coding
tools will generate amazingly looking
code that looks like it's going to work,
but this is complete BS. I'm going to go
ahead and use a feature of Curo called
checkpointing. So, as you interact with
Kuro, there's an ability to essentially
roll back to a snapshot in time. Yes,
you should be using version control.
Yes, you should be keeping track of your
code changes with AI by committing them.
But this goes a step further. So, it's
going to bring us back to the context
that we had at that point in time. And
this is an irreversible change. Now,
we're back to where we were.
>> JPI.
>> This is all hallucinated.
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead.
>> No problem. All right. So now we're
going to take a look at the ghost here
and see on the left the hero pane with
specs, hooks, agent steering, which if
you attended the previous talk, you may
have learned a bit about and MCP. We're
going to start with MCP
and we're going to connect the Strand
agent MCP server to Kira. It's open
source as well as the Strand Agent SDK.
And the easiest way to connect it is to
go to curo.dev and look at the MCP
server directory. There's a one-click
option to add the strands agent. If we
click that, it's now in our JSON
configuration, and I can go ahead and
enable the strands agent MCP server. So
now I'm going to adjust the prompt a bit
and say note
refer to the strands agent MCP server to
get the context you need to build this
code.
Let's keep the code simple for the demo
with only
a few lines. Use the default LLM
>> and let's see what Kira does now.
So you can see it's prompting us if it
has permission to call the MCP tool.
We're going to go ahead and give it
access to do so. And it's going to make
a series of calls with this MCP server
using these search tools to search the
documentation, fetch the documentation,
and that context comes in to the model
which is going to make it generate the
proper code.
At least that's the hope.
>> Indeed. Indeed.
So if we give it a moment here,
it's going to start generating the
Python code we need to invoke the LLM
and generate a DRO. And we see it here.
I'm going to open that up. And I know a
couple of y'all raised your hands with
familiarity with strands, but I
intentionally wanted to introduce
strands today to show how simple it is
to build.
As you see, with just a few lines of
code here, I am building an AI agent.
Now, there is a prerequisite here. I
have configured uh an AWS account with
uh credentials and access to bedrock.
Amazon Bedrock is an AWS service that
allows you to invoke foundational models
such as enthropic claude.
So now that we have this here, I'm going
to
generate steering docs. This concept of
steering for curo allows you to ensure
this context is appended throughout your
engagement with the agent.
I can simply click generate steering
rules as you may for any project that
you'd like to start from scratch or
build features on top of using the Curo
IDE and it's going to generate some
markdown files. So we see a product.
It's a simple dad choke generator using
strands AI. We see structure,
for example, how we organize things and
any conventions or code patterns. And
then the text stack. So we're using
Python, we're using strands.
So now that we have those steering docs,
I think it would be really cool if we
made a multi- aent system here. So we
have this agent here that will generate
dad jokes. I should prove to y'all that
it works. So let's do that.
Let's create a virtual Python
environment.
I'm going to have it install the strands
agent stuff and then run the code.
Kira is going to automatically
open up the terminal and run the
appropriate commands to set up the
Python virtual environment. Pull down
the dependencies required to utilize the
strands agent as well as run the Python
code.
When we run the Python code, it's going
to
open up the agent and say simply tell me
a dad joke. As I was preparing this
demo, I noticed there's a pattern of the
model having a bias for this why don't
scientists trust Adams joke because they
make up everything. So we may see that
again and again. One thing I can do is
and yall remember we can edit code
directly. We don't always have to depend
on the LLM. I'm going to modify the
prompt here to say consider unique
themes to seed the joke.
Don't use the same
trust Adams joke.
All right.
So, now that we have this joke here and
we've seen the value of MCP and
steering, let's build an agent and
deploy it to production using agent
core. Amazon Bedrock Agent Core is a
service from AWS that allows you to run
agents in production at scale where you
don't have to manage infrastructure and
it will scale for you and it has
incredibly unique features that can do
things to make running agents easier.
To do that, I'm going to open up the
agent core MCB server so we can ensure
that the agent has the right tools
to access
the agent core docs and build the agent
core application.
So, I'm going to go over to Kira and I'm
going to edit this. I could literally
just ask Kira to curl this URL and say
figure out how to add the MCP server.
I'm going to
uh I'm going to generate or rather
insert the configuration myself. So I
just pasted in the config from the docs
manually. And now we can see down here
that the MCP server is set up.
So next
and you can see um I've prepared this
prompt. This is a live demo. So this is
definitely non-deterministic. Um, but
you can see I've introduced some
specificity in the context here. For
example, I'm telling it, hey, we're
using agent core for this dad joke judge
we're going to build. The dad jokes
we're generating are now being passed to
a production agent and being judged once
we deploy this system.
We want to be explicit here. Use the
agent core MCP docs. Use the Python AWS
SDK.
use strands
and ensure things like the payload
format and the response structure are
dictated to the LLM so it doesn't go
down a path that we should we don't
expect or hallucinate something that
said it could completely do that and
we're prepared in this live demo for the
unknown.
So now I'm going to go ahead and ask
Hero
about this plan.
And this may be a good task for specs. I
mean, this is pretty detailed here. Um,
but just for the sake of our condensed
time scale, I'm using the vibe mode.
And I'm going to give it permission to
run the agent core MCP tools. So it can
call those docs and get the contacts
that it needs to build this dad joke
agent.
So basically for those who are not
familiar with these some of these tools
obviously we are using kirao and um you
know MCP server to get access to all
these different documentation or the
current information and then strands is
the SDK to build the agent where agent
core is where the agent lives. It can
live on your desktop or somewhere else
but obviously in a production
environment probably it's not going to
be your um your environment right. So
agent core is the um place where it is
completely managed environment for um
agents. So you don't have to deal with u
scaling them or managing them or um you
know different aspects of the agent
deployment.
>> Thank you honor. Just so we're proving
this is real, I'm running the script a
few times to call the LLM and see what
kind of joke it generates.
We got a scarecrow joke. We got a
elevator joke. All great stuff.
So, I know from the agent core docs that
I'm going to need to set up some
dependencies. So, this is the main page
from the docs and I'm going to go ahead
and install this
while hero gets to work on building what
it needs to build. It's dictated
everything here in terms of what it
thinks it needs to do based on the
context that it gathered from the MCP
server of agent core. And I'm going to
go ahead and say yes, go build it.
>> So now we're creating a new strands
agent. This is the dad joke judge.
Python
and Kira's going to figure out how to
get that deployed to agent court.
I have an agent core console instance
open. So this is the AWS console
and when I've deployed my agent, we'll
be able to see it here.
I'm going back to Kira now and I can
already see it's written the code and
it's starting to deploy. Let's take a
look at that code to see how easy it is
to build on agent core.
So you can see the similar concepts from
Strams, right? Simple import,
simple agent prompt,
but we've have we have a couple
additions here. We're importing the
Bedrock core app. We're adding this
decorator.
And this is what less than 20 lines of
code to deploy a production agent in
agent core.
And there we have it.
So Kira is going to keep working because
it's still in this prototype process.
But we can see here that the agent
appears to be deployed. If it wasn't
deployed, it's just invoking a local
version. It indeed here has been
deployed. We see the runtime agent judge
and the time stamp showing it's just
been deployed. And we can see from the
terminal here this response the agent
has been uh pushed to AWS on US East1
with agent core and then we tested it
with a dad joke and got this response
about the joke. You know why it's an
eight and not a 10? Because I didn't
think of it first. Slaps me.
All right. So Kira's going to keep
going.
Um what can I get a time check owner?
Yeah, we're I think almost time to
>> Okay, I know we got a little delayed
because of the setup here, but I want to
be respectful of everyone's time. There
you have it. We've shown today how Kira
and can be used as an AI coding tool to
build agents with strands or whatever
libraries or frameworks you'd like to
use. um as well as concepts like MCP
which is multicontext protocol to have
context resources to your preferred AI
coding tool. Now while we're demoing
with Kirao and strands and agent core
you can apply all these concepts to
whatever kind of tools you prefer to use
and we'd encourage you to experiment
with all the things if you feel inclined
to try out Curo. We'd love to hear your
feedback. We are very very active in the
community listening to the voices of the
developers and getting that stuff on the
road map.
I will pivot back over I think owner you
may have a final
>> yeah so
>> slide here
>> you'll be basically QR code or curo.dev
um since we g a uh product like on
Monday you can go and download and start
using it um today. uh one kind of note
on the AWS uh so obviously we used agent
core here and we deployed stuff so that
will require AWS account however in
order to use kirao you don't need an AWS
account you can actually use uh with
social login or builder ID um so it
doesn't need to have an AWS account to
run um we also have a free tier so you
don't have to pay to art.
>> Anything else?
>> All right. Well, thank you so much for
coming.